Guide to the Doris Duke American Indian oral history project audio recordings 1949-1972
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Mr. and Mrs. Timbimboo (Shoshoni), 1967 July 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 52)
  Chief Washakie Farm, Shoshoni Tribes, LDS Church influence, ceremonies, customs, World War II, stores, life in the past, changes in farming, land claims, education, homes, livestock, Church taking land from Native Americans, Baptisms, famous people of the LDS church, Sawmill, sheep herding, community help, church meetings, cradel board, songs, clothing, polygamy, relations with other Native Americans.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hours 56 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Martin E. Seneca in Washakie, Utah.
- Frank Timbimboo (Shoshoni), 1967 July 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 53)
  Orgin of Chief Washakie, Government and the LDS Church jurisdictions, population, occupations, education, life as ayoung boy, development of the Native American, Federal benefits, medical attention, Washakie-surrounding communities relationships, language, land trusts, classmates, reservation life, economics, Native American culture, U.S. Army-Native American engagements, influence of the LDS Church.
  Interviewed and recorded by Martin E. Seneca, Jr. in Brigham City, Utah.
- Henry Harris Jr. (Northern Ute), 1967 July 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 54)
  Names, trappers, religion, epidemics, shelters, murder-suicide incidents, trade, opening of the reservationallotments, African American troops.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total runnning time 48 minutes.
- Wilson Johnson (Northern Ute), 1967 July 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 55)
  Death of father, Native American Agent, education, views of Native American Bureau, reservations, discrimination, religion, attitudes about horses, wives, children, migration, integration, employment, land development, farming, alcohol, The Sun Dance, differences between Ute and Sioux, introduction to Mrs. Johnson.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 23 minutes.
- Austin Box, Sally Box (Northern Ute), 1967 August 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 56)
  Air force experience, integration, education, Ute-Mountain Ute differences, language, Bureau of Native American Affairs, dependency on reservations, values, Head Start Program, discrimination.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil in Ouray, Utah.
- Margaret Eberly (Non-Native Associated with Northern Utes), 1967 August 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 57)
  Education, vista training, contrast between Ouray and New York City, alcohol, social problems, economics, religion, missionaries, discrimination, raising children, politics, termination, masculinity, family problems, shelters.
  Reel-To-Reel A-Tape, compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 15 minutes.
- Fullmer Allred (Non-Native Associated with Utes), 1967 August 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 58)
  First contact with Washakie, conditions of Washakie, LDS Church activities, Washakie project, Allred's Policy, improvements achieved, Native Americans leaving the Church, land trusts, economics, Native American adjustment, education, population, migration, housing, Native American-Bishopric relations, attitudes of the authorities of the LDS Church.
- Frank Smith (Hualapai), Mrs. Tim McGee-Grandma, 1967 Spring; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 59)
  Frank Smith:
  Medicine, paint, sacred places, a legend, food, songs. Side 1 and 2.
  Mrs. Tim McGee:
  History of Mrs. McGee, names, Native American-Caucasian relations, Apache-Mojave-Hualapai conflict, meeting places, origin of Yavapai, Moki, Supai, Mojave, Paiute, hair, trade, hunting, food, marriage, Medicine Men, pottery, massacres, childbirth, ear piercing, child-parent relations. Her interview begins on side 2 end of track 5.
  Interviewed and recorded by Clifford Purcell in Peach Springs, Arizona.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 60-61)
  Because of the poor condition of the audio recordings these interviews are available only in transcript form. Please see the Doris Duke oral history project in the Manuscripts Division of Special Collections (Ms 417).
- Wallace Dennis, Mrs. Wallace Dennis, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 62)
  History of the Uinta Basin, Dennis family history, history of Mr. and Mrs. George Stuart.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) total running time 29 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded in Myton, Utah.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 63-64)
- Ina Lou Chapoose, Marietta Reed (Ute), 1969 January 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 65)
  Meeker Massacre, hunting, food, gold, medicine, Tea Dance, recreation, population, education, Ute history.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) total running time 32 minutes.
- Recordings unavailable (Reel 66-67)
- Patrick Bankatewa (Zuni), 1967 August 01; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 68)
  Origin of the Zuni, the Devil and how he joined the Zuni, serach for the heart of the Earth, seperation of the Band, origins of names and places, people on Earth before Zuni, killing giants, revelations about the White Man, origins of names of animals, scalp dance, Mrs. Stevenson's attempts to collect information about the Zuni.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 2 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by D. Corydon Hammond in Zuni, New Mexico.
- Louis Caywood (Non-Native Associated with Zuni), 1967 August 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 69)
  History of old Church structure, excavated personal items, burial of children, building tequniques, relations between excavaters and community citizens, crying sands, pottery.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total riunning time 34 minutes.
- Wilbur Hunt (Acoma), 1967 August 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 70)
  In this interview, Wilbur Hunt discusses incidents and relations between Spaniards and Acoma, Relations between Catholics and Native Americans, and Native American traditions.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 28 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by D. Corydon Hammond in Albuquerque, New Mexico.
- Vedna Hunt (Non-Native American Associated with Laguna), 1967 August 19; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 71)
  Ancestors, Zuni voting, Cha' Kwena Order, rituals, Religion, Caucasian-Laguna relations, intermarriage, epidemics, traders, Spanish-Laguna relations, Acoma-Laguna relations.
  Available compact disc copy ( 1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 5 minutes.
- Wilbur Hunt (Acoma), 1967 September 03; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 72)
  In this interview, Wilbur Hunt discusses subjects including famines, farming, life in the Pueblo in 1910, recreation, a gift from Abe Lincoln, native dances, education, and traders.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 53 minutes.
- Recording unavailable (Reel 73)
- Emil Pooley (Hopi), 1967 September 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 74)
  First contact with Spanish, Spanish-Hopi relations, effects of Catholic Missionaries, destruction of Awatobi people, clans, dealing with the U.S Government, village without men, Imprisonment, forced schooling, chief Dan, epidemics, famines, communal disinfectant baths, retrieving captured Squaw.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (74-78), compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 16 minutes.
- Merle Sheka (Zuni), 1967 August 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 75)
  Coming of the Spanish, Pre-Spanish days, religion, Battle of Sacred Mountain, life on Sacred Mountain, Zuni-Hopi relations, Zuni-Spanish relations.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (74-78), compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 51 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by D. Corydon Hammond in Gallup, New Mexico.
- Father Emanuel Trockur (Non-Native American Associated with Navajo), 1967 August 11; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 76)
  History of St. Michaels, language, Mother Kathrine Education, uprising, life in the early days, railroads, books, land, allotments.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (74-78), compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 24 minutes.
- Chester Gaspar (Zuni), 1967 August 28; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 77)
  The coming of the Spanish, religion, migration, Zuni-Apache relations, livestock, mission, arts and crafts, Spaniard-Native America relations, life on Sacred Mountain, famines, trade, clothing, farming, witchcraft, Scalp dance, Mormon-Zuni relations, White War Chief.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (74-78) compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 5 minutes.
- Clara Gonzales (Non-Native Associated with Zuni), 1967 August 19; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 78)
  Personal arrival at Zuni, education, tuberculosis, food, twins, reaction to White Culture, recreation, World War II, economics, The Great Depression, Government Doctors, sword swallowing ritual, Kiva Dance, Parent-Teacher relations, impeached Governor, factionalism, public utilities.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (74-78), compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 2 minutes.
- Bowman Paywa (Zuni), 1967 July 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 79)
  Origin of Zuni, Life on Sacred Mountain, Kachina Dance, Zuni-Apache-Navajo relations, Scalp Dance, Scalping Custom.
- Dewey Haskie (Zuni), 1967 July 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 80)
- Merle Sheka (Zuni), 1967 August 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 81)
  Measles epidemic, famines, water, trade, caucasian-Native American relations, shelters, clothes, transportation, education, religion.
- Sue Marmon (Laguna), 1967 August 20; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 82)
  Mrs. Marmon's ancestry, early schools, missionaries, early settlers, livestock, relations with the: Paguate, Apache, Acoma, Navajo, Ute. Religion, written Constitution, breakdown of communal work, contributions of the Marmons and Gunns, self government, scalping custom, Laguna-San Jose picture incident, land controversy, history of Laguna Village of Paguate, famines, epidemics, experiences at mission school.
  Interviewed and recorded by D. Corydon Hammond in Old Laguna, New Mexico.
- Bowman Paywa (Zuni), 1967 August 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 83)
  Childhood, prophosies, clothes, food, shelters, White War Chief, epidemics, famines, arts and crafts, livestock, livestock reduction, education, stick race, recreation.
- Bowman Paywa (Zuni), 1967 August 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 84)
  Missionaries, religion, Tribal Government.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (84-89), compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 53 minutes.
- Bowman Paywa (Zuni), Bruce Pascali (Zuni), 1967 August 01; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 85)
  Legend:. Translation by Bownam Paywa.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (84-89), compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 23 minutes.
- Bowman Paywa (Zuni), Bruce Pascali (Zuni), 1967 August 01; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 86)
- Margaret Lewis, (Cherokee Associated with Zuni), 1967 August 29; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 87)
  Pueblo life in the early days, education, dances, Measles epidemic, clothing, courting, marriage ceremony, religion, catholic-Zuni relations, witchcraft, African American Medicine Man, farmers, traders.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (84-89), NO CD
- Chester Gaspar (Zuni), 1967 September 01; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 88)
  Farming, stock reduction, trade, traders, religion, politics, transvestites, African American Doctor, medicine, epidemics.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (84-89), compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 5 minutes.
- Bowman Paywa (Zuni), 1967 August 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 89)
  Politics, impeachment, World War II, education, governorship.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (84-89), compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 32 minutes.
- Dewey Haskie (Zuni), 1967 September 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 90)
  Withches, shelter, food, clothes, traders, livestock, Aqua-Queena, farming, medicine men, transvestites,Catholic-Zuni relations.
  Translated By Roland Lemantino
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (90-95), compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 53 minutes.
- A. Bond (Non-Native Associated with Zunis), 1967 August 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 91)
  Settlement of Ramah, Caucasian-Native American relations, rituals, trading, education.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (90-95), compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 37 minutes.
- Joseph Otero (Non-Native Associated with Zunis), 1967 September 04; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 92)
  Politics, church (mission) restoration, Tribal Government.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (90-95), compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 49 minutes.
- Merle Sheka (Zuni), 1967 September 05; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 93)
  Zuni-Apache-Navajo relations, religion, White War Chief, withcraft, rustlers, salt, transvestites, stick race, Cactus Society, alcohol, education, prophesies.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (90-95), compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 1 hour 3 minutes.
- Father Emanuel Trockur (Non-Native Associated with Navajo), 1967 August 21; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 94)
  Early St. Michaels, the Hogan, names, language, Charley Mitchell, burial, religion, superstition, economics, population, peyote, polygamy, burial of a priest, witchcraft, rugs, arts and crafts, weaving, U.S Government-Native American relations, education, smallpox epidemic, stock reduction, law, alcohol, trade, St. Michaels Press, books.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (90-95), compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 2 hours 5 minutes.
- Ronnie Paquin (Zuni), 1967 August 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 95)
  Religion, Witchcraft, medicine men, missionaries, Bureau of Native American Affairs, education, alcohol, generation gap.
  Reel-to-reel audiotape (90-95), compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 28 minutes.
- Bowman Paywa (Zuni), 1967 September 06; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 96)
  Cactus Society, Battle of Sacred Mountain, sword swallowers, medicine societies, dance, religion, masks, Kivas.
- Margaret Lewis (Cherokee Associated with Zuni), 1967 August 30; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 97)
  Anthropologist-Zuni relations, religion, stock reduction, World War II, The Great Depression.
- Dewey Haskie (Zuni), 1967 September 05; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 98)
  Education, farming, Warren Ondelacy Impeachment, jewelry, Tribal Law, Zuni-Anthropologist relations, alcohol, medicine men, generation gap.
  Translated by Roland Lemantino
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 25 minutes.
- James Stewart (Non-Native Associated with Navajo), 1967 July 10; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 99)
  Sawmill, Red Cross, reservation uprising, World War II, Stock reduction, Leaders, Peyote, communication.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 59 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Alva Matheson in St. Michaels, Arizona.
- Carl Jake, Roy Tom (Paiute), 1967 July 21; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 100)
  Native names
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 4 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Kay Fowler in Cedar City, Utah.
- Carl Jake, Roy Tom (Paiute), 1967 July 20; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 101)
  Termination, agents, farms, tourism, names, land.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 56 minutes.
- Margaret Heaton (Non-Native American Associated with Kaibab), 1967 July 14; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 102)
  Farming in the early days, Inited Order and the Native Americans, childbirth, clothing, Native American-Caucasine relations, farming, discontinuation of the United Order, trade, food, land disputes, polygamy, agents and superintendents, experimental medicine, Native American-Mormon relations.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 5 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Kay Fowler in Moccasin, Arizona.
- Stewart Snow (Paiute), 1967 July 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 103)
  Water rights, termination, Paiute-Caucasian relations, land, cattle sale, employment, missionaries.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 8 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Kay Fowler in St. George, Utah.
- Stewart Snow (Paiute), 1967 July 27; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 104)
  Religion, alcohol, agents, medical services, ancestors, Vietnam.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 July 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 105)
  Birthplace, names, education, food, plants.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1 hour 6 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Kay Fowler in Kaibab, Arizona.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 July 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 106)
  Plants, foods, medicine, the story of Sage Hen, Paiute-Navajo relations, names, food gathering, trade, Ute-Paiute relations.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 July 19; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 107)
  Powell, bathing customs, shelters, native plant names.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 32 minutes.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 July 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 108)
  Medicine, food, native names of plants and animals, Caucasian-Native American relations.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 July 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 109)
  Farming, living places, employment, education, Agents, food gathering, native names of animals, native names of canyons, Navajo-Caucasian relations.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 July 25; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 110)
  Religion, food, native names of plants, soap, tobacco, dance, hunting, language, doctors, Ute-Paiute relations, salt, flu epidemic.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 July 26; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 111)
  Buffalo, utensils, food, Religion, story-telling, Paiute-animal relations, food sources.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 35 minutes.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 August 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 112)
  Life in Kaibab, language, Caucasian-Native American relations, money, names, farms.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 August 08; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 113)
  Land grants.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 12 minutes.
- Mabel Dry (Paiute), 1967 August 12; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 114)
  Names, food, native names for seasons.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 55 minutes.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 115)
  Elders, names of places.
  Interviewed and recorded by Kay Fowler and Robert Euler in St. George, Utah.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 15; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 116)
  Meanings of Native American names, life in and around Bryce Canyon, fighting within families, relation to Kaibab Tribe, changing names, Smart Project, life around Kanab in the early days, shelters, education, life with the Heaton family.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 117)
  Life in Carlisle, health, living quarters, education, return to Utah, cattle, Caucasian-Native American relations, establishment of a school, Mormon-Native American relations, religion, recreation, the Ghost Dance, the Prophet Dance, songs.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 118)
  Social life, Religion, personal background, education, summer employment, first train ride, travel to Pennsylvania, horses.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 16; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 119)
  Origin of Paiute, cliff dwellers, enemies of Paiutes, trade, names, tribal wars, funeral ceremonies, Ute-Paiute relations, child stealing, Jacob Hamblin, fights, food.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 120)
  Food, language, plants, early White families, education, protection from the Navajo, shelters, water supply, names, camping, water, babies, names of springs and lakes, tale of harmful water and monster, Toney's son, Shivwit Reservation, land and farming, Chiefs, cattle.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 121)
  Shiprock, Shoshoni-Paiute connection, loss of Kaibab, names, Deer, Antelope, plants, hunting, pine nuts, land, mining, tribal council, health service, Medicine Men, intermarriage.
  Available compact disc copy (2 CDs) Total running time 1hours 6 minutes.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 122)
  Reservation names, Virgin River, canyon names, old camping places, "Park Monster", hunting, Paiute words and their meanings.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 123)
  Paiute names of places, Chief Walker, Chief Kanosh, springs and lakes, land claims, medical services, land leases.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 124)
  Land rights, missionaries, superintendents, cattle business, tribal council, early reservation life, hunting rights, cooking techniques, pine nuts, rabbits, arts and crafts, fire making, tools and weapons, clothes, Major Powell, Shivwit Chief.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 18; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 125)
  The death of three White Men, Major Powell, Kanab in the early days, animal names, plant names.
- Toney Tillohash (Paiute), 1967 June 19; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 126)
  Fort Pierce, Paiute names for tribes, Paiute names of places, names of people, schooling, welfare, alcohol, Peyote, Shoshoni-Ute relations, trade.
- Andrew Honina, Haddie Arriwhite (Shoshoni), 1967 March; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 127)
  Historical Tales and Legends:, personal reminiscence of Honina.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 6 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Lorin Gaarder in Pocatello, Idaho.
- Andrew Honina, Haddie Arriwhite (Shoshoni), 1967 March; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 128)
  Historical Tales and Legends:
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 11 minutes.
- Andrew Honina, Haddie Arriwhite (Shoshoni), 1967 March; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 129)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 27 minutes.
- Andrew Honina, Haddie Arriwhite (Shoshoni), 1967 March; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 130)
- Andrew Honina, Haddie Arriwhite (Shoshoni), 1967 March; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 131)
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 21 minutes.
- Andrew Honina, Haddie Arriwhite (Shoshoni), 1967 March; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 132)
- Andrew Honina, Haddie Arriwhite (Shoshoni), 1967 March; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 133)
  Historical Tales and Legends Haddie Arriwhite:
  Kwasinsimi with General Howard, two brothers bring horses.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 10 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Lorin R. Gaarder in Pocatello, Idaho.
- Andrew Honina, Haddie Arriwhite (Shoshoni), 1967 March; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 134)
  Andrew Honina:
  Haddie Arriwhite:
  Two brothers bring horses, Kwasinsimi with General Howard, battle of four groups of Native Americans.
- Clifford Pete, John Pendelton (Paiute), 1968 January; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 136)
  Arts and crafts, clothes, Chiefs, marriage, songs, Caucasian-Native American relations, rustling, names, Chief Walker, Parowan.
  Available compact disc copy (1 CD) Total running time 54 minutes.
  Interviewed and recorded by Alva Matheson in Parowan, Utah.
- Roy Williams (Southern Ute), 1967 September; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 137)
  Farming, differences between tribes, language, hunting, Spainiard-Native American relations.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil and Gregory C. Thompson in Ignacio, Colorado.
- Oscar Bitsie (Navajo), 1967 AUgust 24; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 138)
  Grammer School, High School, College training, getting Native American children to go to school, Native Americans and the Christian Churches, Shalako Club, language posing a problem for Native American students, concept of time, Navajo sence of humor, Native Americans and Civil Liberties, Mr. Bitsie's job as a school attendance officer, intermarriage, family relationships, acculturation.
  Interviewed and recorded by Floyd A. O'Neil and Gregory C. Thopmson at The Fort Lewis College in Durango, Colorado.